Michael Döringer



I am a highly motivated Data Analytics rookie with a background in journalism, copywriting and 10+ years experience in the music industry. Knowledgable in statistics, ML models and data visualization, passionate about data, SQL and Python. I am looking for a entry level Data Analyst position preferably with a technical focus.

Languages

German (native), English (fluent)

Address

Innstr. 30, 12043 Berlin

Phone

+49 160 94872921

Mail

doeringer.michael@gmail.com

https://hugolargo.github.io/

Education

2023

Data Analytics Boot Camp

Spiced Academy Berlin

[Python, Pandas, SQL/PostgreSQL, Tableau etc.]

2011-2014

Cultural Journalism (MA)

Universität der Künste Berlin (UdK)

2008-2011

Popular Music and Media Studies (BA)

Universität Paderborn

Professional experience

2020-2022

Music Data Editor & Team Lead Musicology

Moodagent Deutschland

- preparation of the German music catalogue for a new streaming service
- responsibility for the database, focus on metadata and content operations
- monitoring and improving the Al supported music recommendation system
- collaboration with global teams in DK, IN, AUS/NZ
- leading a team of 4 people

2017-2020

Cultural Validator for Apple Marcom

via Hogarth Worldwide

- approval of content for marketing purposes in GSA
- selection and analysis of music, movies, tv shows, books, audiobooks, map locations

2015-2020

Lead Copywriter for Apple Music DE

via Hogarth Worldwide + Bridgehead Media

- original writing, editing, localization and translation
- shaping the editorial voice of Apple Music since its launch in 2015
- 5000+ playlist descriptions, album notes, hero blurbs, artist bios, email and website copy
- participated in workshops with Apple in London

2014-2020

Freelance editor and writer

for magazines, online media and record labels

- Universal Music: digital catalogue curation, editorial consulting, playlist creation
- Monkeytown Records and Morr Music: PR work
- regular contributor to publications like Spex,
 Groove, Das Filter, Mixmag, Electronic Beats, Vice
- interviewed artists like: Grimes, Paul Kalkbrenner, Rhye, Modeselektor, DJ Koze, Goldfrapp, Mike Skinner, Moby, Tiga, Tortoise and many more

2011-2013

Contributing editor

De:Bug Magazine

- · planning of monthly printed magazine issues
- supervising review section
- realization of cover stories and extend features
- mentoring of freelance writers and interns
- · editing, proof-reading and layout adjustments